Year 991 of the Holy Era
Rio...
We haven't evaluated your
academic abilities yet,
but I was wondering, can you read and write?
No. I've never studied writing, so...
I see. Then, I'll tutor you!
Come to my research lab after school.
It's in the basement of the library tower.
Thank you.
Oh, and...
Yes?
Many of the children here are from
royal or titled families, so...
In the beginning, they may be a little...
It's all right.
What?
I know my place.
I see.
But if you have any problems, please don't
hesitate to come to me, all right?
I will.
Welcome to the Beltrum Royal Academy!
Seirei Gensouki
Royal Academy
Huh? Who is that?
A transfer student?
A transfer student will be joining this class
starting today. His name is Rio.
I've never seen him before.
Everyone, be nice to him, all right?
So, he's the transfer student
from the slums, huh?
The slums?
Someone as lowly as that is joining
our glorious Royal Academy?
I heard that he saved Princess Flora,
so His Majesty, the King,
approved his enrollment.
On this occasion, you have done well in
saving my daughter. I give you my thanks.
Your words do me too great an honor.
I am both humbled and delighted.
Very good.
Then, we shall have you attend the
Royal Academy's primary school
as a scholarship student.
Rio?
Introduce yourself to everyone.
Yes, miss.
My name is Rio.
Through the kindness bestowed
upon me by His Majesty, the King,
I have been allowed to attend
this place of learning.
I know that I am lacking in many ways,
but I hope that you will
look favorably upon me.
Very nice.
It seems he can speak as
well as a servant, at least.
Well then, Rio, if you'll
take a seat there, please.
Yes, miss.
All right, everyone, we're starting our lesson.
Let's all study hard again today.
Yes, miss.
Open up your notebooks and copy
down this numerical formula.
Now then, everyone try solving
these problems on your own.
Yes, miss.
These are so easy.
Rio?
You don't need to push yourself
too hard today, all right?
Yes, miss. Thank you for your concern.
I don't think he can read.
All right, everyone. Focus on your work.
Where is it?!
There was a hint hidden in that paper!
Where has it gone?!
Is this it?
Professor Celia?
Oh, honestly!
Can't you read the sign?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I can't read.
Rio?
I came to inquire about my
private tutoring, but...
Yes! Well done in coming here.
I've been waiting for you. Yes!
She completely forgot, didn't she?
W-Well then, come in.
Yes, miss.
Please, excuse my intrusion—
I-It's just a tiny bit messy at the moment.
I see.
U-Usually, I'm much more organized.
Just a moment. I'll make us some space.
There are a lot of
difficult-looking books here.
But you look so young, Professor.
Hm? Oh, yes.
I'm still only twelve, after all.
What?
Really, I should be attending
primary school,
but I skipped grades and ended up
graduating from high school.
You must be quite brilliant.
W-Well, I suppose.
I've finished.
A-Already?
What? This is amazing!
All your answers are correct!
And you did it so quickly with
only mental calculations...
Well, it was only simple
multiplication and division.
Once I understood how to write
the numbers and symbols...
Simple?
Pretty much the only one in your class
who can do this is Princess Christina.
What? I-I see.
Well, that makes sense.
I...
was a university student, after all.
Rio...
Where did you learn arithmetic?
From my mother, who died.
I see.
Your mother was quite cultured.
Yes.
She was a kind and warm person.
I'm sorry for making you think of her.
Don't be. I'm fine.
That's a relief. I'll make
us some tea, all right?
Here you are. Please, have some.
Thank you.
It's very good.
I'm glad you like it!
When you drink a good cup of tea...
It just makes you feel happy, doesn't it?
Rio?
Yes?
How was your first day of academy life?
Please, tell me. Did you have any problems?
No.
Nothing in particular.
I see. Well, if there is anything—
In that case, just one thing.
What is it?
Will you recommend me some children's books?
Books?
I want to learn my letters.
Oh... Yes.
I'll pick out a few for you from the library.
Thank you.
One, two, three, four, five!
One! Two! Three!
Four! Five!
Stay agile!
One, two, three, four, five!
Rio.
Y-Yes, Sir?
One, two, three, four, five!
Come and strike me in any way you see fit.
What?
Yes, sir.
Interesting.
What? Huh?
What?
What kind of stance is that?
That stance is weird.
Now, attack.
Now, Haruto!
Don't hold back. Attack!
Don't hesitate!
Good swordsmanship.
Advance!
Haruto!
Don't dodge it!
Drive toward your opponent's chest!
Instead of evading to the outside,
he drove toward his opponent.
His form isn't right at all.
It seems there's no end to his vulgarity.
All right. That's enough.
Rio, you have the makings
of a knight, indeed.
I'm terribly sorry,
but I have no interest in joining the knights.
Really...
I thank you for your kind words.
What?
What did he just say?
That's crazy.
Rio?
Yes?
You're even studious after classes end.
End-of-term exams are coming up soon.
You've only just enrolled here. You don't
need to worry about your grades too much.
I won't.
But I'll give it everything I have.
Very good.
Does everyone have an examination paper?
Yes, miss.
Then, begin!
Yikes! Um...
One, two, three...
Mouths closed, everyone!
Everyone, do your best!
Mii...
...chan.
There he is.
Is that him?
Really?
A kid from the slums enrolled here.
His Majesty, the King, is pretty eccentric.
Ayase Miharu was...
Amakawa Haruto's childhood friend.
But when Haruto's parents divorced,
the two of them were separated.
Then I saw Mii-chan again in high school...
and that was it.
She never came back to school.
It was as though she'd erased
herself from my sight.
And what of it?
Amakawa Haruto is dead.
Right now, I am Rio.
I'm not Amakawa Haruto anymore.
That's why...
I will live through this.
I will be tenacious and strong.
This can't be right!
It can't be.
That guy?
Really?
Alongside Princess Christina?
That's impossible!
I'm third?
You've got to be kidding me!
This must be some kind of mistake!
That's right!
Hey, he's here.
You! What impropriety have you perpetrated?
What do you mean?
That!
A commoner like you
could never stand with Princess Christina
at the top of the class!
Anything other than fraud is unthinkable!
Top of the class?
You must have used some kind of dirty trick!
I simply took the exam, that's all.
Liar!
Leave it, Alphonse.
The jealousy of a gentleman is unsightly.
I-I can't let this pass unchallenged!
I will have this injustice—
Do you have any concrete evidence?
That's...
Unsubstantiated allegations only serve to
sully the dignity of the academy.
But...
This achievement is the result
of Rio's hard work.
I can attest to that.
Professor Celia...
I will never accept this!
Let's go.
Yeah.
Thank you for—
It was nothing. And I didn't
intervene for your sake.
I see.
You won't beat me next time.
Rio!
Congratulations on placing
first in the end-of-term exams!
Thank you.
To tell you the truth...
I'm a little worried.
Worried?
Yes.
When I think that even more students may
look for ways to find fault with you...
I'm used to it already.
Oh, dear.
This bullying by nobles shows poor
character on their part, you know.
Professor Celia, you said that you excelled.
Did anything similar happen to you?
Well, this and that from those of a higher
social standing and their followers.
I ignored all of it, though.
Just as I thought.
I-In my case, I had friends!
Then, I'll be fine, too.
What?
I have you, Professor Celia.
Huh?
What?
Oh, Rio!
Yes?
You're making fun of me, aren't you?
Treating me like a child!
But you're older than me, Professor.
Y-Yes, but... well... it means you
think of me as a friend, right?
Yes.
Would you rather I didn't?
I... don't mind.
What?
Will you say it just one more time, please?
I...
I said I don't mind! You're so mean, Rio!
Figure it out from the mood,
can't you? Honestly!
Then...
If ever I'm in trouble, advise me as
my teacher and as my friend, won't you?
O-Of course!
When you're about to cry from all
the bullying, I'll take you to my bosom.
You're small, so in terms of positioning,
you do seem perfect for clinging to.
Don't say "small"! I'm still growing!
Oh, we're the perfect heights.
Yes.
Oh, Rio, you silly!
Year 966 of the Holy Era
An exhibition tournament between the knights
of the realm will be held again this year.
Representatives for the primary school
division have been selected from this class.
If your name is called, step forward!
Sixth-year, Alphonse Rodan!
Sir!
Fifth-year, Stewart Huguenot.
And...
Rio!
What? It can't be true.
Step forward!
Sir.
Him? Why?
Wait!
What is it?
I cannot accept this.
For someone so lowly to have been chosen to
participate in a knightly tournament...
That's right!
It is a disgrace!
Besides, he can't even use magic.
It has already been decided.
No objections will be entertained.
But how?
I just can't accept it.
I heard you'll be participating
in the tournament.
Yes, well...
If you do well in the tournament,
the knights may scout you even
before you graduate, you... know.
I have no intention of becoming a knight.
Rio...
Yes?
You've gotten taller, haven't you?
What?
Well, I suppose it has
been five years already.
Professor...
What is it?
You're still just as small
as ever, aren't you?
Don't say "small"!
I'm still growing, I tell you!
You said the same thing five years ago.
Hmph!
The tea will get cold.
Oh...
Such a lovely aroma!
It's so good!
They're the same leaves,
but when you make the tea, Rio,
the scent is completely different!
I simply follow the instructions
I read in a book.
You say you have no intention
of becoming a knight.
What will you do after you graduate?
I thought I'd go on a journey.
What?
There's somewhere I'd like to go.
Then... you plan to leave this country?
This country...
is difficult for me to live in.
That may be so, but...
Why don't you work here?
What?
Without you around,
all sorts of things will go wrong.
That's not true.
You see? The way you tidied here...
It's so clean!
And you make such wonderful tea!
You always chide me when I get too
caught up in my research. And...
I'm grateful for your consideration, but...
Professor, sooner or later you'll
enter into marriage talks, won't you?
What's this all of a sudden?
It wouldn't be good to have some
unknown commoner in your research lab.
I've no intention of getting
married for a long time, though.
Well, I'm sure you're free
to do as you like, Professor.
Hey! You're thinking I'm going to miss
my chance to get married, aren't you?
Professor Celia, you look so youthful
and lovely, I'm sure you'll be fine.
So you're saying I look like a child.
Not at all. You're a charming woman.
D-Don't tease me like that.
What was that?
Oh! Um, well... Where is it
that you want to go, Rio?
My parents' homeland, the Yagumo region.
Yagumo? The place at the
edge of the wilderness?
Yes.
When you're bigger, I'll take you there.
It's a place called Yagumo.
Really? You promised, okay?
Rio?
I-It's only a plan at the moment.
Rio...
Now, the tournament between the
glorious knights of the realm
and the students of the
Royal Academy will begin!
And I, Alfred Emerle, unworthy as
I am, will serve as referee today!
As noble as ever!
Emerle-sama!
Beltrum Royal Academy primary school!
First challenger, Rio! Stand forward!
Hey! Don't put on a pathetic
performance out there.
You'll lower people's opinions of me as well.
I will do my best not to
fight an unsightly match.
No one is expecting anything from you anyway.
Rio!
Keep it together!
I am ready to begin.
Good.
And from the Knights of the Royal Guard,
the first challenger,
Charles Arbor!
I knew you'd enrolled in the academy,
but I'd never have imagined that the
dirty little brat from back then
would be my opponent.
I owe you a debt for your care of me back then.
I was so very sorry I couldn't
have been of more help.
Cease your chatter.
Challengers at the ready!
What is that stance?
He doesn't have a shield. Is he mocking me?
Begin!
Rio's amazing!
He's staying calm and parrying the blows.
Because of you, I was punished
with a demotion five years ago!
I will never forget that humiliation!
H-Hold on!
How could a knight fight so
seriously against a student?!
Now, Rio!
What?
This will finish you!
Hold!
The winner, representing the academy, is Rio!
W-Wait, please!
I let down my guard. That's all!
What?
I'll fight for real next—
Idiot!
A loss is a loss!
Alfred...
Charles.
If you are a member of the honorable
Knights of the Royal Guard,
you will graciously accept your
defeat and take your leave.
I-I admit my defeat.
Thank you for the match.
Very good.
Amazing! Amazing!
Indeed.
Rio, was it?
I look forward to his future.
Blast that annoying brat!
If I'd been serious, I would have won!
In that sort of situation, it isn't so
bad to let the students take the glory.
With no understanding
of such consideration,
in the end, the other Knights
of the Royal Guard all won.
Dear, dear. How childish of them.
Th-That's right!
I let him take the glory!
Just as you'd expect from the Honorable
Ambassador of the Proxia Empire.
You understand!
And that student who fought against you...
Huh?
He certainly moved very well.
That brat!
Five years ago,
it was thought he might have been
involved in Princess Flora's kidnapping.
At the time, I investigated vigorously, but...
In the end, he never talked.
I see!
So you two were fated
to face each other, then.
I don't know about fated.
I see. From back then...
I hope he comes soon. I need
to celebrate his win with him!
Rio!
I wonder where he's going.
H-Here. Please, read it!
What is it?
Y-Yesterday's match!
You were so... so very dashing!
So gallant!
Oh! Excuse me!
Wait, you there!
Next Time
Kingdom of Lies
"Kingdom of Lies."
Spirit Chronicles
Exciting Bonus Manga
By Minazuki Futago
stare
She's
watching
me...
I-It's not
as though
I'm looking
at you out
of affection.
Don't get
the wrong
idea!
Do
not
get
the
wrong
idea!
Huh?
Right...
I
won't...